=His Chosen Favor=
=مفضلته المختارة=
(The nest of tenderness, not the path of thorns, will trap us)
(سيوقعنا في الفخ عش الحنان، لا طريق الأشواك)
=Episode 18=
=الحلقة 18=
Yindan.
من يين.
Your Highness, you're awake.
يا صاحب السمو، أنت مستيقظ.
Fu An, where's Yindan?
فو آن، أين يندان؟
I don't know. Please save His Majesty!
لا أعرف. أرجوكم أنقذوا جلالته!
His Majesty might be in grave danger.
قد يكون جلالته في خطر جسيم.
Where is His Majesty?
أين جلالته؟
He went to Zhongcui Mountain to save you.
لقد ذهب إلى جبل تشونغكوي لإنقاذك.
Zhongcui Mountain?
جبل Zhongcui؟
Yes.
نعم.
How long has he been gone?
كم مضى على رحيله؟
Two hours.
ساعتان.
Fu An, prepare a boat for me.
فو آن، جهز لي قارباً.
Yes.
نعم.
Xiao Wenjing.
شياو ون جينغ.
Where are you, Xiao Wenjing?
أين أنت يا شياو ونجينغ؟
Xiao Wenjing!
شياو ون جينغ!
How are you, Xiao Wenjing?
كيف حالك شياو وينجينغ؟
Your poison was cured?
هل شُفيتَ من سمّك؟
I don't know what happened.
لا أعرف ما حدث.
Soon after you left the palace,
بعد مغادرتك القصر بفترة وجيزة،
my poison cured.
لقد شُفيتُ من سمّي.
(Before leaving the palace,)
(قبل مغادرة القصر،)
(Yindan gave Zhen'er the antidote).
(أعطى يندان الترياق لـ Zhen'er.)
(She just tricked me into taking the poison).
(لقد خدعتني للتو لأتناول السم).
Well.
حسنًا.
Take a rest.
خذ قسطاً من الراحة.
I'll find the antidote.
سأجد الترياق.
Don't take him away!
لا تأخذوه بعيداً!
Consort Xi!
القرينة شي!
Put him down
أنزله أرضاً
and I'll let you go.
وسأدعك تذهب.
Whether you are human or ghost,
سواء كنت إنسانًا أو شبحًا،
Xiao Wenjing did not kill you.
لم يقتلك شياو وينجينغ.
Why seeking revenge on him?
لماذا تسعى للانتقام منه؟
I'm letting you go.
سأتركك تذهب.
Don't kill the wrong target.
لا تقتل الهدف الخطأ.
If I kill him,
إذا قتلته،
you can marry Prince Rui
يمكنك الزواج من الأمير روي
and leave the palace with Yindan.
ثم يغادر القصر مع يندان.
Why are you helping him?
لماذا تساعده؟
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
This
هذا
is the bracelet I gave Yindan.
هذا هو السوار الذي أهديته إلى يندان.
Yindan?
من يين؟
Don't call me that.
لا تناديني بذلك.
I'm not Yindan!
أنا لست من يين!
Yindan,
من يين،
why do you want to kill him?
لماذا تريد قتله؟
I said I'm not Yindan!
قلتُ إنني لستُ يندان!
Fine, you're not Yindan.
حسنًا، أنت لست يندان.
You are Consort Xi.
أنتِ القرينة شي.
But why do you want to kill him?
لكن لماذا تريد قتله؟
Naturally,
بطبيعة الحال،
blood must be paid with blood.
يجب أن يُدفع ثمن الدم بالدم.
She said the late emperor caused her parents' wrongful deaths.
وقالت إن الإمبراطور الراحل تسبب في وفاة والديها ظلماً.
She infiltrated the palace
تسللت إلى القصر
to seek revenge on me.
أن يسعى للانتقام مني.
What?
ماذا؟
I don't want to be your enemy.
لا أريد أن أكون عدوك.
Yindan,
من يين،
Xiao Wenjing didn't kill your parents.
لم يقتل شياو وينجينغ والديك.
I vouch for it with my honor.
أشهد على ذلك بشرفي.
There must be misunderstanding.
لا بد من وجود سوء فهم.
I heard it with my own ears.
سمعت ذلك بأذني.
The murderer said it himself
قال القاتل ذلك بنفسه
the late emperor ordered him to eliminate us.
أمره الإمبراطور الراحل بالقضاء علينا.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
did you know it or not?
هل كنت تعلم ذلك أم لا؟
No.
لا.
I had no knowledge of it.
لم أكن على علم بذلك.
Of course you wouldn't know me.
بالطبع لن تعرفني.
My parents and I
أنا ووالداي
were nothing but ants to you,
لم يكونوا بالنسبة لك سوى نمل،
so you don't know us.
إذن أنت لا تعرفنا.
Yindan.
من يين.
He wouldn't.
لن يفعل.
He, he wouldn't.
هو، هو لن يفعل.
If you don't leave now,
إذا لم تغادر الآن،
I'll kill you too!
سأقتلك أنت أيضاً!
Go!
يذهب!
If you don't let him go,
إذا لم تتركه يرحل،
kill me as well.
اقتلني أنا أيضاً.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why are you helping him?
لماذا تساعده؟
Yindan,
من يين،
I'm not helping him.
أنا لا أساعده.
He is certainly not a good man,
إنه بالتأكيد ليس رجلاً صالحاً،
but he does not lie.
لكنه لا يكذب.
I don't want you to kill the wrong target.
لا أريدك أن تقتل الهدف الخطأ.
Yindan,
من يين،
believe me.
ثق بي.
Please
لو سمحت
believe me one more time.
صدقني مرة أخرى.
Stop suspecting Yindan.
توقف عن الشك في يين.
Everyone in this hall answers to me,
كل من في هذه القاعة مسؤول أمامي،
except her.
باستثناءها.
It absolutely couldn't be her.
لا يمكن أن تكون هي بالتأكيد.
I've investigated it thoroughly.
لقد بحثت في الأمر بدقة.
Yindan's father, Lou An, a Medical Pavilion academician,
والد يندان، لو آن، أكاديمي في الجناح الطبي،
offended the late emperor and got his family executed.
أغضب الإمبراطور الراحل وتسبب في إعدام عائلته.
She is here for revenge.
إنها هنا للانتقام.
She has gone mad.
لقد جنّت.
To avenge, she harmed you.
لقد آذتك انتقاماً.
Even if she hurt me,
حتى لو آذتني،
don't harm her.
لا تؤذيها.
Here's the antidote. Take it.
هذا هو الترياق. خذه.
I'll help you
سأساعدك
uncover the truth.
اكشف الحقيقة.
So Her Majesty's fire was also your doing?
إذن، هل كان حريق جلالة الملكة من فعلك أيضاً؟
Yes.
نعم.
For my revenge,
انتقاماً مني،
all royals must die.
يجب أن يموت جميع أفراد العائلة المالكة.
Why didn't you kill Prince Rui too?
لماذا لم تقتل الأمير روي أيضاً؟
He just returned from the frontier.
لقد عاد لتوه من المناطق الحدودية.
He's clean, not like you.
إنه نظيف، ليس مثلك.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Skip Prince Rui.
تجاوز الأمير روي.
Yindan,
من يين،
how did your parents die?
كيف توفي والداك؟
My father, Lou An, concocted elixirs for the late emperor.
كان والدي، لو آن، يصنع جرعات سحرية للإمبراطور الراحل.
That morning,
في ذلك الصباح،
he told me and my mother,
أخبرني أنا وأمي،
his elixir would be completed that day.
سيكتمل إكسيره في ذلك اليوم.
Once the elixir was finished,
بمجرد الانتهاء من تحضير الإكسير،
he would take me and my mother away
كان سيأخذني أنا وأمي بعيدًا
from the capital, a troublesome place.
من العاصمة، وهي مكانٌ مُثيرٌ للمشاكل.
But that day, my father
لكن في ذلك اليوم، والدي
didn't return even until the Zi hour.
لم يعد حتى الساعة العاشرة مساءً.
My mother and I couldn't wait any longer,
لم نعد أنا وأمي نستطيع الانتظار أكثر من ذلك.
so we decided to sleep.
لذلك قررنا النوم.
We had just lain down when we heard noises.
كنا قد استلقينا للتو عندما سمعنا أصواتاً.
My mother pushed me into the cellar.
دفعتني أمي إلى القبو.
The next day,
في اليوم التالي،
when I crawled out of the cellar,
عندما زحفت خارج القبو،
I
أنا
only found her corpse.
لم يعثروا إلا على جثتها.
So,
لذا،
you infiltrated the imperial selection
لقد تسللت إلى عملية الاختيار الإمبراطوري
to assassinate Xiao Wenjing?
لاغتيال شياو ون جينغ؟
Yes.
نعم.
But I never expected that selection
لكنني لم أتوقع هذا الاختيار أبداً
wasn't for the new emperor's consorts,
لم يكن ذلك من أجل زوجات الإمبراطور الجديد،
but for burial consorts.
لكن بالنسبة لمرافقي الدفن.
I never expected to meet you.
لم أتوقع أبداً أن ألتقي بك.
You saved me.
لقد أنقذتني.
This wasn't my doing.
لم يكن هذا من فعلي.
Seems more like Empress Dowager Chen's doing.
يبدو الأمر أقرب إلى فعل الإمبراطورة الأرملة تشين.
But the guards in black clearly said "His Majesty".
لكن الحراس الذين يرتدون ملابس سوداء قالوا بوضوح "جلالة الملك".
I heard it very clearly.
سمعت ذلك بوضوح تام.
You mean
تقصد
I sent them to kill you,
أرسلتهم لقتلك،
and asked them to tell you it's my order
وطلبت منهم أن يخبروك أن هذا طلبي
and let you go,
وأتركك تذهب،
so that eighteen years later,
بحيث بعد ثمانية عشر عاماً،
you'd come back to kill my family?
هل ستعود لقتل عائلتي؟
I'm not that stupid.
لستُ غبياً إلى هذا الحد.
Wait.
انتظر.
I feel it is
أشعر بذلك
a bit strange.
غريب بعض الشيء.
What's strange?
ما الغريب؟
It's hard to explain.
من الصعب شرح ذلك.
Yindan,
من يين،
did your father
هل فعل والدك ذلك؟
succeed in making the elixir?
هل نجحت في صنع الإكسير؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
He rarely spoke
نادراً ما كان يتحدث
of the elixir-making.
من عملية صنع الإكسير.
If he had made it,
لو أنه نجح،
the late emperor wouldn't have died.
لم يكن الإمبراطور الراحل ليموت.
True.
حقيقي.
Yindan, don't cry.
يندان، لا تبكي.
I'll help you uncover the truth.
سأساعدك في كشف الحقيقة.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Why are you apologizing?
لماذا تعتذر؟
I used you.
لقد استغليتك.
But you didn't harm me.
لكنك لم تؤذني.
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
From now on, let's live well together.
من الآن فصاعداً، فلنعيش معاً حياة طيبة.
Tell me whatever troubles you.
أخبرني بكل ما يزعجك.
I'll help you.
سأساعدك.
Okay.
تمام.
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
I've lifted your house arrest.
لقد رفعت عنك الإقامة الجبرية.
Why don't bake back at the Zhaohua Hall
لماذا لا نخبز مرة أخرى في قاعة تشاوهوا؟
instead of here?
بدلاً من هنا؟
Yindan's birthday is coming.
عيد ميلاد يندان قادم.
I'm preparing a surprise for her,
أُحضّر لها مفاجأة،
so can't bake at the Zhaohua Hall.
لذا لا يمكن الخبز في قاعة تشاوهوا.
You really treat her well.
أنت تعاملها معاملة حسنة حقاً.
Of course.
بالطبع.
She's my own sister.
إنها أختي.
After I celebrate her birthday,
بعد أن أحتفل بعيد ميلادها،
I'll help her find the murderer.
سأساعدها في العثور على القاتل.
She is indeed your own sister.
إنها بالفعل أختك.
Scheming meticulously and playing tricks
التخطيط بدقة ولعب الخدع
to preserve that image
للحفاظ على تلك الصورة
of the perfect sister in your mind.
عن الأخت المثالية في مخيلتك.
It means she genuinely cares for me.
هذا يعني أنها تهتم بي بصدق.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm hungry. Getting a snack.
أنا جائع. سأتناول وجبة خفيفة.
Go to the imperial kitchen for food.
اذهب إلى المطبخ الإمبراطوري لتناول الطعام.
I have no food for you.
ليس لدي طعام لك.
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
I came alone to save you.
لقد جئت وحدي لإنقاذك.
Aren't you touched?
ألا تتأثر؟
Well, I saved you too.
حسناً، لقد أنقذتك أنت أيضاً.
If it weren't for me,
لولا أنا،
you'd have died.
لكنتَ متّ.
I'm very grateful for that.
أنا ممتن جداً لذلك.
And you?
وأنت؟
You dragged me into this!
لقد جررتني إلى هذا!
You charging to your death to save me
أنت تندفع نحو موتك لإنقاذي
is just what you owed me!
هذا بالضبط ما كنتَ مدينًا لي به!
Why should I be touched?
لماذا يجب أن أتعرض للمس؟
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
you're heartless.
أنت عديم الرحمة.
No, I'm not.
لا، لست كذلك.
But your petty favors
لكن خدماتك التافهة
can't erase the pain you caused me.
لا يمكنني محو الألم الذي سببته لي.
Now leave.
انصرف الآن.
I need to finish this cake.
أحتاج إلى إنهاء هذه الكعكة.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
Rise.
يعلو.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
I've long wished to tell you something.
لطالما رغبت في إخبارك بشيء ما.
Do not fail Her Highness.
لا تخيبي ظن صاحبة السمو.
I understand.
أفهم.
Why summon me again?
لماذا استدعائي مرة أخرى؟
My cake isn't finished!
لم تكتمل كعكتي بعد!
Look.
ينظر.
(Succession to Lu Zhen'er)
(خلافة لو زينير)
An edict of succession?
مرسوم بالخلافة؟
Yes.
نعم.
Passing the throne to me?
هل ستسلمون العرش لي؟
Are you insane? Or dying?
هل أنت مجنون؟ أم تحتضر؟
I've thought it over.
لقد فكرت في الأمر ملياً.
You were right.
كنت محقاً.
Even if I return to the real world now,
حتى لو عدت إلى العالم الحقيقي الآن،
I probably won't adjust to the modern life.
ربما لن أتأقلم مع الحياة العصرية.
Better to live well here.
من الأفضل أن تعيش حياة كريمة هنا.
Cherish the present.
استمتع باللحظة الحاضرة.
But that doesn't mean abdicating to me!
لكن هذا لا يعني التنازل عن العرش بالنسبة لي!
Don't you want to be Empress Regnant?
ألا تريدين أن تصبحي الإمبراطورة الحاكمة؟
I don't.
أنا لا.
That's bitter toil.
هذا عمل شاق ومرير.
Can't beat
لا يُضاهى
the joy of being a lazy slacker.
متعة الكسل والتكاسل.
But previously...
لكن سابقاً...
I wanted to be Empress Regnant,
كنت أرغب في أن أصبح الإمبراطورة الحاكمة،
because you made me the target of all.
لأنك جعلتني هدفاً للجميع.
You made me realize
لقد جعلتني أدرك
that in this harem,
ذلك في هذا الحريم،
without power, survival is impossible.
بدون طاقة، يصبح البقاء على قيد الحياة مستحيلاً.
The nest of tenderness, not the path of thorns,
عش الحنان، لا درب الأشواك.
will trap us.
سيوقعوننا في الفخ.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
if you sincerely love me
إذا كنت تحبني بصدق
and protect me,
واحمني،
perhaps I'll remain Consort Lu,
ربما سأبقى القرينة لو،
indulging in pleasure under your wing.
الاستمتاع بالمتعة تحت جناحك.
But even if I spare you
لكن حتى لو أبقيتك على قيد الحياة
and treat you with sincerity,
وسأعاملك بإخلاص،
you'd fight for justice for the people,
ستناضل من أجل العدالة للشعب،
because of the world's unfairness.
بسبب ظلم العالم.
You pity the weak,
أنت تشفق على الضعفاء،
yearn for universal harmony.
نتوق إلى الانسجام العالمي.
You seek power, not for yourself.
أنت تسعى إلى السلطة، لا لنفسك.
Even immersing in tenderness,
حتى في خضم الحنان،
you'd rage against those who abuse power
ستثور غضباً على أولئك الذين يسيئون استخدام السلطة
and moved by the wretched
وتأثروا بالبؤساء
clinging to life.
التشبث بالحياة.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
what's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
Don't put a heavy filter on me.
لا تفرض عليّ قيوداً صارمة.
Truthfully,
بصراحة،
you're a good person.
أنت شخص جيد.
Stop sweet-talking me!
توقف عن مغازلتي!
I'm not sweet-talking you.
أنا لا أغازلك بالكلام المعسول.
I want to reconcile.
أريد أن أتصالح.
Reconcile?
تصالح؟
It's not that simple!
الأمر ليس بهذه البساطة!
I need to observe you longer.
أحتاج إلى مراقبتك لفترة أطول.
How long?
حتى متى؟
Depends on my mood.
يعتمد ذلك على مزاجي.
Come on.
تعال.
Celebrate Yindan's birthday with me.
احتفلوا معي بعيد ميلاد يندان.
- ♪Happy birthday to you♪
- عيد ميلاد سعيد لك!
♪Spring comes late after the snow♪
يأتي الربيع متأخراً بعد الثلج.
♪Having endured sorrow and joy♪
بعد أن تحملنا الحزن والفرح
♪Wandering the streets, the story unfinished♪
أتجول في الشوارع، والقصة لم تكتمل.
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
عندما استدرت، فقدتُ أثرك.
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي.
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
لقاؤنا محجوب بضوء القمر؟
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
أرجو أن تمنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان.
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
???تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف؟؟؟
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح.
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
الشوق ينسج في شبكة.
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر.
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
ومع ذلك، أتوق إلى نظرتك.
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
الزمن، تاركاً وراءه الكثير من الماضي.
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
الخراب يتبع المجد
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا؟
♪Will I kiss your face♪
هل سأقبل وجهك؟
♪Never forgotten, hope you've been well♪
لن ننساك أبدًا، أتمنى أن تكون بخير.
♪Borrowing the first ray of spring light♪
استعارة أول شعاع من ضوء الربيع؟
♪Can it bring about for us?♪
هل يمكن أن يحقق لنا ذلك؟
♪One look back, lasting till the end of time♪
نظرة واحدة إلى الوراء، تدوم إلى نهاية الزمان.
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح.
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
الشوق ينسج في شبكة.
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر.
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
ومع ذلك، أتوق إلى نظرتك.
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
الزمن، تاركاً وراءه الكثير من الماضي.
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
الخراب يتبع المجد
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا؟
♪Will I kiss your face♪
هل سأقبل وجهك؟